I think in the last bull market, people got greedy and they didn't just get greedy financially.
They got greedy with the assumptions that the community.
So if this is the theory, why do you think the price might crash?
The ETF will make it easier for money to flow into Bitcoin, but I think it will also make it
easy for money to flow out of Bitcoin as well. I think overall it will lead to more investment
in Bitcoin. It will lead to a larger market cap. We're going to see the projects from last time
rise to all time heights. Are we going to see more new projects actually raised to all time
heights? Are you ready for an amazing episode? Because today we have a very special guest.
We're excited to have Ben Rogers with us today. He's the head of sales and marketing at Flipster.
He's had some incredible experiences working with industry giants like Google, Flight Center,
Travala.com. And today Ben will share his insights into the crypto marketing world
and his perspective on the future of crypto.
Let's welcome Ben Rogers.
My name is Ben. I'm the head of marketing with Flipster.
What was the challenge you face?
So my background professionally is within the travel space. So I've worked in airlines,
I've worked in the hotel sector, and I worked for insurance, primarily travel insurance. And it was
this kind of experience that landed me a job in crypto. So I was actually several years ago now,
I'm approached by a girl who was an intern of mine a very long time ago at a company I worked for.
And she was with a crypto OTA, so an online travel agency called Travel by Bit. And it's from there that
I got my first crypto job, if you will. So what they did is they had an airline OTA that allowed
people to book flats as you would anywhere else, but you could pay with crypto. And they also had a
payment gateway at the time too, which they had rolled out through airports across Australia that
was allowing people when they got off a flight to pay with Bitcoin or Litecoin. And it made a bit of an
attention. Shortly after I joined, Binance actually took a majority stake in that company. And then it wasn't too long
until we actually purchased Travala.com. And I was their first CMO. And so some of you guys might have heard of
Travala.com. They're still going really strong. But that was my journey into crypto. From there, I've worked for a
number of different projects of all different drives and NFTs through to ICOs. I've done a bit of consulting as well, too,
for some really big exchanges. And now I've ended up here at Flipstar. And I would say this is probably my favorite of the
crypto companies I've got to work with yet.
So from a person that don't know crypto much, how do they land like a job in crypto?
I would encourage them to look at what their previous experience has and why a crypto company would need
that when they're putting together their resume or they're applying for jobs. It is an industry that is
very much about making connections with who you know. So sitting around online and just kind of hoping
that, you know, someone's going to read your resume when you apply for a role is maybe not the best way to do it.
I encourage you to get out there, you know, try to reach out to people online and get connected, have a chat with them.
If there are events in your city that are crypto related, go talk to some people in person.
You're going to need that network. But the cool thing is, is once you break into the crypto industry, from my experience,
it's really easy to keep going. Right. It's really easy to get the next job or work with some more people.
But yeah, the first hurdle I've heard for many is quite hard.
Yeah, let's talk about Korea. Why is crypto trading so popular? People trading crazy volume.
What's your observation?
I'm not Korean myself. So the assumption I would make here is lots of disposable incomes,
perhaps within Korea for one, they've got the money to do it. But on our platform, particularly,
they seem to really like our competitions. So we run like, say, the Dragon's Treasure,
or previously when we've done different trading events, both volume based and P&Ls,
Koreans tend to really be quite competitive. Some guys in Korea remember a mobile app.
This is a true story. I promise it is true, everyone. We had one guy that in a single day on a mobile app
had more than 10,000 trades that he did on his app. More than 10,000 trades.
Yeah, open, close, open, close, open, close.
That is insane.
Yeah, that was insane. That was insane. You know, if you calculate the time of the day,
you know, we looked into it. We didn't think it was possible, but it was. It was as well.
Is it a bond-related type of thing?
That's what we thought it was, but then we looked into it. It was not a bot. We do not have an API
to our platform. You've got to be trading yourself.
Wow.
What is the crypto scene like in Australia? Because we talk about crypto in Korea and Asia,
but I don't know much about crypto in Australia, to be honest.
It's a good question. So I think comparatively to Korea and Singapore, it's not as exciting. It's
definitely not as big as Asia, but it's certainly there. Last bull market, I think like the tax office
in Australia reported something like about one in 25 people had crypto in one way or another.
That has come down since the bull market. I believe I saw a study recently that it was much,
much lower. There's 25 million people in Australia about that. So it was a relatively
high adoption. You know, they're keen to try it. In my city where I come from, downtown area,
into the bull market and after that as well too, we had multiple point of sale systems that you would
see regularly in cafes or bars as well that allow people to make crypto payments. So it is something
that people are involved in. The government in Australia, I think, hasn't really made a decision
on what they want to do as it goes to regulations. And so that I think is creating some uncertainty
there. I think Australia will pick up. I think if we go into the next bull market, we will see a lot
more of Australian projects. And that's where I got started in crypto too. So I shouldn't,
you know, discount that. Travel by Bit was in Australia. And then Travala.com, its CEO,
was actually in Perth at the time. So there are people making moves in crypto that come from Australia.
So you're working for Flipster now. You said it's your favorite place to work so far.
Why Flipster and what's so different about Flipster?
I mentioned we are very, very smart people in our financial engineering team.
Our team is actually able to list stuff faster than Binance.
So generally what we do is if we hear Binance is going to list something at, you know, XYZ time,
we've got it on our platform first. And I know a lot of our new traders have been applying that
into their strategies as well when they join us on the platform. So yeah, credit to the team.
And I know they put in a lot of hours to get that up and running. But it is a demonstration of,
again, fast, which is a theme for us. There's an assumption within the industry that when
Binance lists a project that that token is going to pump. That's generally what people think.
I don't know if it's true or not. I can point to situations where it definitely wasn't true.
But there is a perception about it. So us as a derivatives platform,
and we try to be quite generous to it, the leverage that we can apply. People are coming in and they're
sort of thinking what the Binance listing is going to have for the token if they're a short term trader.
But they might also be thinking about it. And there's like some of our big trades,
there's some of our big wins that we've seen people have.
They were looking at what it might mean over the next three or four weeks.
The token's now on Binance. It's now more readily available.
It's easier for people to buy in more places. So that's what they're applying to their strategy.
And us being able to have it first means they're able to
make a decision before that happens as to what they think will happen to that token.
But why are we different to other projects? Was that part of the question?
Different to other exchanges.
We're a new exchange. And we're trying to do one thing very, very well right now.
For exchanges that are mature players in the market, you open their app, they do lots of things.
They have spot trading, they have earning, they have copy trading, and a variety of other features
that they might have as well. And so that can create challenges on its own, right? You got
distracted users, you potentially have competition of what part of the product I should work on.
With us, we're trying to do derivatives really well. And we're starting with a mobile first approach.
So whereby other apps have maybe been desktop first, and then they've switched back into the app,
we're going in the other direction. So I think that's really cool and interesting for one.
And it is working, right? It is working.
Like right now, there are people in the market who's teasing that the bull market might be back.
At Flipster, it's been bullish all year round.
We're growing at about 550% month-on-month user base. I think our average trading volume
growth has been 4,000% this year. So it's working.
Can you tell us more about the founder? I heard they are in quant trading.
Founders at Flipster set up Presto Labs. It'll be 10 years next year. If you're not familiar with
Presto Labs, guys, they're probably the largest quant trading firm within Asia. And based on volume
on Binance, they're definitely one of the biggest. They've partnered with lots and lots of projects
in crypto. They've got lots done. Last year, publicly, they did about 500 billion in volume
on their platform. But what I'm getting at here is these guys know how to build a business.
These guys know the crypto industry. They know trading. And for them, an exchange was a way for
them to bring those skills, bring the knowledge that they have, and refocus it now into a B2C market.
So beyond the crypto, I do a lot of stuff with startups, right? And one of the things I've
noticed is the startups that tend to make it are the ones where the founders come from the industry,
right? They're not trying to learn it. So I think these are the right people to set something like
this up. There are a lot of exchanges out there, big ones, matured ones, new ones. Why is this a good
time to start an exchange? It's a great question. So I was talking about things that I see during
startups that are successful. And I talked about people come from the industry. The other one is
timing. So why now is a great time is we've been in a bear market. I don't think that's controversial
to say. And we've seen a lot of projects, tokens and exchanges the like go broke. So the previous
generation of exchanges hadn't successfully cornered the market in the last bull market. There's capacity
for a new exchange. And with us being self-funded effectively by our founders, the bear market was
the perfect time to build. The bear market was the perfect time to get ready with a new product.
And that's why now is the right time. So if you can make it in a bear market as an exchange,
you're far more likely to make it when the bull market comes around and attention hopefully swings
back in favor of crypto. What I absolutely love about Flipster is how fast we're getting stuff done.
I'm a pretty impatient and kind of competitive guy. So sitting around in a boardroom and, you know,
talking about projects for six months before we start has never really been something that has
particularly I've enjoyed. So here we move really quickly. You know, it can be the start of the day.
We will have an idea. And we're starting to put that into execute that by the end of the day.
The founders here are very data driven. They're very data focused. And in some other crypto companies
I've been with, they haven't necessarily been as kind of commercially minded as maybe they could have
been. And so having that, you know, going to be accountable to numbers or making sure you're
growing or making sure things is heading in the right direction. I think it creates a really good
culture. So for me at Flipster, that's probably why I'm enjoying it so much.
Would you call this a Korean crypto exchange? Because the founders are Korean, right?
It's not a Korean crypto exchange. So the founders are Korean. They're all based in Singapore.
So our company is registered in Sissos. We have a license in Poland. That's a pretty recent news.
And then the holding company is in Singapore. The founders themselves met in the United States
a long time ago where they set up their business. In the company, you guys might look at me,
you might notice I'm not Korean. We all speak English and we have a team all around.
You're from Australia, right? I'm from Australia, yes.
Let's talk about the competitors. Who are your main competitors right now?
I consider us to have the crypto competitors and then I consider us to have the entertainment
competitors. And I'll jump into the easiest one first being the crypto competitors. So all the
exchanges that have derivatives trading products are technically our competitors. So you've got,
you know, Binance, KuCoin, OKEx, etc. Now on the other side of that, we have the entertainment
competitors. And so what I argue is like a product like Instagram in a way is a competitor for us.
Or Netflix is potentially a competitor for us. Or a news business is a competitor for us.
And the reason why that is the case is we are on an app. And so when people are trading with us,
they could be doing entertainment type activities as well too, scrolling Instagram,
scrolling New York Times or something like that. So we're actually getting them interested in crypto
and making, you know, maybe highly leveraged fast trades with us on a token they haven't seen.
And so we're cutting into that time as well, which I think is fun. And it's another angle for us as
well when you were thinking about an exchange that we're competing for attention of a user,
which is the way social networks or Netflix or something like that, they kind of grow their
businesses. It's very hard to attract attention and it's very expensive as well, right? What are you
guys doing to attract, let's say, users who are scrolling Instagram or Facebook? What is Flipser doing to
attract users? I'll take this from maybe the product design perspective. So we've brought in some
designers who have worked for very, very big companies in the tech space, generally over within
the United States and brought them over to Asia. So they're familiar with a lot of the tactics that
are used in these apps to make them interesting and make them engaging to people. We're starting with
that there. We're not bogged down as well with a large amount of features. So if you're a legacy
product out there, you have a very advanced product probably in terms of the endpoints of your APIs for
what can happen, all the different features you have in them, and you kind of jam all that into
an application. When we've gone the other way, we've been able to take attention, take UI from the very
beginning, and then just add in the little bits that we need. With our marketing, which is more my part
as well, we want to earn your attention. So if you are on our social networks and I encourage you to take
a look, I hope you see an evolution of us getting more and more interesting and more and more creative
what we're putting out there. We want to earn your eyeballs and we don't want to take them for granted.
So that's a big piece of what we have as well. When we get users into our ecosystem, we have a very
sophisticated direct marketing approach as well. My strategy with direct marketing is I want to get
to a point where potentially 99% of emails that you receive are unique. So no one else has seen them.
We're dynamically building them around you, what you're doing on the app, what you're interested in,
what you want to see, because we want to earn your eyeballs. We don't want to take you for granted.
We're just like a standard newsletter that's sent to X number of other people. So again, I think it goes
to, you know, we're talking about fast as one of our core values. I think earning attention is another
thing that we're keeping front of mind.
You said you've worked at really big exchanges before, right? What's the company culture compared to Flipster?
So we have a lot of ex-people from big companies inside of Flipster. They're not necessarily
all crypto first. You know, they're bringing experience from tech and then we're teaching
them about crypto. But in the important roles, like the Fin engineering team, they're all very
crypto heavy and academically so as well. In the bigger company that I worked for, at the time,
I think a lot of hiring was done around people who are potentially passionate for crypto.
You know, let's face it, the last bull market or the one before, you know, there were a lot of people
who didn't think this was going to work out. And so you need to have passion because you want to have
people that are quite loyal. Everyone here is very kind. Everyone here is very aligned. And I love
that in the culture. I think we're all realists to what's going on. And maybe the other company I
worked for, a lot of people passionate about crypto. And that was kind of the primary thing that needed,
people needed to be when they were hired. And then they were sort of like, you'll learn the job as you go.
Have you noticed some changes after, let's say, Luna and FTX? What are the companies
crypto companies doing differently to minimize the risk?
I think in the last bull market, people got greedy. And they didn't just get greedy financially,
they got greedy with the assumptions that the broader community, like the normies,
beyond those in crypto, would just keep coming. And we burnt a lot of trust as an industry.
We destroyed a lot of people. Lots of people lost money. Lots of people lost faith in friends that
said I should buy this thing and go there. And it was exceptionally damaging. And it is exceptionally
damaging. I don't think people are going to fall for those tricks anymore. I think people are aware
of the tricks. And I think people are looking for products that seem safe and secure. But what I would
point to is, if I'm looking at the big guys, and I hope we're trying to do this as well, we're treating
crypto like it is a mainstream brand now. And we're doing the kind of activities that a mainstream
brand would do to build trust in their product. We're very worried about reviews. We're very
worried about the perception of our product. We take crash reports extremely seriously.
Customer service, we're online for 24-7 for guys if they have questions. As we're tailoring our
approach to bringing users in, we're being very gracious when people are even trusting us with their
KYC information before they bring it in, before they even put money on the exchange or make a trade.
A comment maybe on Binance for a quick second. I think I've looked at their marketing a lot.
You know, in the last six months, I would describe it as mature. Now, I would describe it as very
mature in what they're doing. They have a lot of safety content, a lot of security-focused stuff.
And they do, in a way, set the trend for this industry. And so I think that what's going on is
that we know we've got to earn the trust and we shouldn't just expect it.
Let's talk about the potential approval of Bitcoin's spot ETF, right? Everyone's talking about it.
How do you think this will impact the crypto industry?
My hypothesis is when it goes through, there'll be a big, big pump that day for Bitcoin. I think
there could be a big pump for other tokens as well as attention comes back to Bitcoin. I think we will
get mainstream media to have stories about it on the day that it happens. And then I think there will be
a correction.
Why is that? Because I've been reading a lot of reports and a lot of specialists are saying it's
going to double, triple the market cap, right? And like other generations, for example, our parents
are going to invest or are more likely to invest in this ETF instead of actually buying a Bitcoin
during an exchange. So if this is the theory, why do you think the price might crash?
The ETF will make it easier for money to flow into Bitcoin, but I think it will also make it easy
for money to flow out of Bitcoin as well. I think overall it will lead to more investment in Bitcoin.
It will lead to a larger market cap, but I'm perhaps not as bullish on it. Maybe some other
people are for what it will do to the price and that price long term. And I do think people will,
and I do think there'll be periods of time potentially where, you know, quantitative easing,
people might feel more comfortable parking their money in Bitcoin. But what I suspect would happen
for mainstream investors, not all of them, you know, some people will be happy that it's to get there,
is that if there is an opportunity for, say, an overcorrection in a tech stock, where a tech
stops down 40% that has a nice dividend or these things, they're probably still going to be more
attractive to investors and they would shift their money back into it. I see the ETF as kind of
ensuring that we'll keep having full markets, actually. Now, people are talking regulations will
kill that off. I think it's going to help that to keep happening because money will flow easily
between mainstream and crypto. But that's my hypothesis.
Regulations, I think the fact that, you know, people are facing consequences for having done
the wrong thing now, you know, even without regulations, the fact that people are going
to jail for this will make it scarier to, you know, maybe pump a project up so much or create
unrealistic expectations of long term gains in crypto. So I do see that probably coming down.
But I think it's ultimately a good thing. So for everyone who's made lots of money in crypto,
we've got to remember there were people who lost a lot of money for them to make money.
And the crypto industry as a market cap itself compared to the bigger financial markets or the
bigger housing market is tiny. So if we want to grow the market cap of crypto, I think we need to
create a market that is more stable for bigger traders to come in. And those bigger traders are not
necessarily in crypto. If they are, they maybe only got a couple of toes in comparatively to what's
going on in the rest of their portfolio. And so regulation will make it safer. There's the
potential to that maybe insurance products can start to come in for crypto as well, too, which will bring
more people's money in. But I do think we will kill off the 100x, the 1000x overnight, which
was very fun last bull market, I'll be honest.
With the high inflation rate, unemployment rate, people are expecting the economy to be bad right
next year. Do you think there is a bull run coming?
I do think there is a bull market coming. We have now more people who have had positive experiences
in crypto. Yes, we've had people who've had a lot of negative experiences in crypto.
That when the traditional markets, perhaps, you know, if there is an economic crisis and,
you know, people do a run on, say, Wall Street or start dumping the big stocks and they've now got
cash somewhere, they're going to want to put it somewhere, right? They're going to want to reinvest
it if they have funds. And I think crypto as kind of the rebel, the anti-establishment kind of brand
for investing will have a place in that.
A lot of people think this is the last huge bull market we'll ever see because of the regulation.
So you don't think this is the case?
No, I definitely do not. I think there are many, many bull markets to come.
And the bull markets in crypto will happen even long after I'm dead.
What are the trends and narratives you've seen that people are talking about recently?
And what's going to be the huge thing in the next bull run?
I think you mentioned it. I think a lot of people are expecting the ETF to kick it off.
I don't necessarily think they're wrong. Because I think the big thing for the ETF is going to be the
front page stories. If we look at the mainstream media for crypto, you know, what's been on the front
page has been FTX, right? It's been SBF. It's been that scandal. That's what's making the front
page. We haven't had really a good story. I can't think of one this year that's been on the Washington
Post, the Financial Times for crypto. So I think that will be your, oh, sorry, the Ripple. Maybe
when Ripple beat the SEC. And I think that had a really nice pump on it, actually, when that happened
as well. So like people float into Ripple, people float into the market. So I think that will happen.
That will perhaps garner more media attention. People will want to report on how this goes.
People want to report on the craze again. I think that can be the catalyst that perhaps
starts the next bull market.
What are some projects that you're paying attention to?
Flipster. And everyone should be paying attention.
Anything else?
I'm biased. I'm biased. For me, I'm looking at what I bought into last time.
Right. So I still have a lot of AVA, Travolos token. I have a lot of DOT. Right. And I've
watched that just. That's good. I hope that comes back. I have a fair bit of Polygon.
So I'm keen to see where that one goes. And ETH. But I'm a big ETH guy. ETH is my top 10 token.
That's what I've always been a big fan of. So I hope we see ETH reach new heights. But I'm also
looking at maybe what, you know, if Polygon doesn't make it, you know, that's a little bit shaky
right now. I am curious to see what project might be the replacement as the layer two there. So
we'll see. What I want to know from the bull market, though, this time, and I don't have an answer for
this, but my question is, are we going to see the projects from last time rise to all-time heights?
Are we going to see more new projects actually raise to all-time heights? And I'm not sure which
way it's going to go. But that's what I'm watching out for.
What is your personal investing strategy? For example, you're all in on Bitcoin, Ethereum.
How does it work for you?
I look at ETH. So I always want to be buying ETH. And I want to find projects that I think are
undervalued. And I'm also interested in what the market situation is as well. So I put a lot of faith
when I'm doing sort of spot trading on what the media is going to care about, right? What the
mainstream media is going to pick up because that gets attention, that brings more people into a
project. But I'm always bullish on ETH. I will be looking to start making some buys soon. I use
Bitcoin as an indicator because when Bitcoin booms, you know, more often than not, maybe other deserving
projects can follow suit. So I'll be waiting for perhaps a correction in Bitcoin. And then I'll be
jumping into some things and be looking to hold them for a while.
Anything else you would like to share with our audience?
You guys need to download Flipster. And we have the Dragon's Treasure, which loads and loads
of prizes as well, too, for trading. We're actually giving away more than a million dollars
in our prizes with that competition between now and the end of the year. But yeah, great time to jump
into Flipster. If we are right and there's a bull market next year, you can be practicing your
strategies and ready for all the fun that is in store for us.
That is wonderful. Ben, thank you so much for joining us today. I find this very insightful,
wonderful, your experience. And it's actually very fun chatting with you.
Anything else you would like to add?
I don't think I have anything else.
Sorry, Ben.
I'm done.